Guide to the Course of Study Committee, Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Course of Study Committee, Yale College, records
1910-1990
RU 595
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
(14 boxes)
The records consist of reports, correspondence, minutes, and subject files documenting the actions and deliberations of the Yale College Course of Study Committee.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-D (YRG 9-D), Records of Yale College committees.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, correspondence, minutes, and subject files documenting the actions and deliberations of the Yale College Course of Study Committee.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Universities and colleges -- Curricula; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Curricula
- Reports, 1910-1912; Accession 1933-A-005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Records, 1926-1971; Accession 1973-A-007
  - General
    - 1948-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Minutes and Correspondence
    - 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
    - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
    - 1966 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 26-30)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
    - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 34-38)
    - 1968 (Box 5, Folder 39-42)
    - 1968 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - 1969 (Box 6, Folder 44-49)
    - 1969 (Box 7, Folder 50-52)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 53-54)
  - Subject Files
    - Bulletin announcements (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Curriculum Changes, 1936-1943
      - Architecture-Economics, Departments of (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - English, Government and International Relations, Departments of (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - History, Department of (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - History, The Arts and Letters, Department of (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - History of Art-Music, Departments of (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Naval Science and Tactics-Philosophy, Departments of (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Physics-Sociology, Departments of (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Interdepartmental majors, Programs of (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Changes in multiple departments (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Departmental majors: report, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Departmental statistics for the President's Committee on Educational Policy, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Educational policy and procedure: proposal for a standing committee on, undated (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Four-course plan: impact upon programs of concentration, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - History and Appreciation of Art, Yale Plan for Education in: report, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - History of the Social Sciences, Program for a School of: report, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Ph.D. and B.A. degrees and the Latin requirement: report, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Programs of study: general reports and regulations, 1926-1944 (Box 9, Folder 72-74)
    - Programs of study: revision of the first two years of undergraduate curriculum: news release, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Programs of study: standard, Scholars of the House and experimental: report, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Programs of study: war time reports and regulations, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Religious education: report, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Science and Engineering, Problems of: report, undated (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Report on the committee on the [illegible] general faculty of Yale College, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Statistics, 1932-1942 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Summer term: curriculum, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - War emergency, prepared departmental programs for the, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 83)
- Course of Study Committee records, circa 1977-1990; Accession 2001-A-071
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026.
  - African American Studies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Studies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Applied Math (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Applied Physics (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Astronomy (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - British Studies (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Biology (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Classics (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Computer Science (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Devane (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - East Asian L and L (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Economics (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Electrical Engineering (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - English (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - E, P, and E (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Film Studies (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - F and ES (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - French (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - GandG (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - German (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - History (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - History of Science/History of Medicine (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Luce (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Judaic Studies (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Humanities (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Italian (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - History of Art (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Judaic Studies (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Latin American Studies (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Linguistics (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Literature Major (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Henry Luce Course (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mathematics (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Mech. Eng. (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
  - Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Music (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Near Eastern Languages (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Operations Research Organization and Management (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Philosophy (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Physics (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Political Science (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
  - Psychology (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Religious Studies (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Renaissance Studies (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Russian and East European Studies (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Slavic Languages and Literature (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Sociology (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Spanish (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Statistics (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Studies in the Environment (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Study of the City (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Teacher Preparation (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Theatre Studies (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Women's Studies (Box 4, Folder 61)